Guide to the Arundell Family, Letters and Documents
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Letters and documents concerning various members of the Arundell family].
1665-1680
OSBORN FB42
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.06
(1 volume)
Manuscripts, in multiple hands, of ten business letters and legal documents concerning members of the Arundel family. The collection incldues two bonds of payment; several money orders; and two letters from R. Arundel to Sir Robert Clayton, drawing Clayton's attention to a "young lady of a considerable fortune," asking for Clayton's assistance in marriage-making for Arundel's son, and explaining what he would be willing to settle upon the couple.
Arundel family
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fb42. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Legal documents; Marriage -- Great Britain; Nobility -- Great Britain; Great Britain -- Social life and customs -- 17th century; Correspondence; Clayton, Robert, Sir, 1629-1707; Arundel family
- Osborn fb42
  - GREAT BRITAIN. SOVEREIGNS, ETC., 1603-25
    - Letters patent (copy) to Thomas Howard, Earl of Arundel and Surrey (1586-1646) for holding the Court of the Constable and Marshal, 1623 Aug 1 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      1 p.; 26 x 19 cm.
      Endorsed: "Coppy of the Lettrs.
      patent to Thomas Earl of Arundell for
      holding the Court of the Constable
      and Marshal 20 Jabs. 1 aug."
      James I, King of Great Britain,
      1566-1625; Great Britain. Earl
      Marshal. Great Britain.
      Court of Constable and Marshall.
  - ARUNDELL OF TRERICE, RICHARD ARUNDELL, BARON, D. 1687
    - Document, signed, 1667 Dec 25 (Box 1)
      Signed and sealed bond by Arundell
      and Richard Scawen on a printed form,
      promising to pay £200 to Edward
      Hinton, goldsmith of London.
      1 p.; 30 x 19 cm.
      Witnessed by Claudius Pettit and
      George Bucknor, with their
      signatures.
  - ARUNDELL OF WARDOUR, THOMAS ARUNDELL, BARON, 1633-1712
    - ALS to Sir Robert Clayton (1628-1707), 1665 May 5 (Box 1)
      n.p.
      concerning payment to William Staley
      (Stayley) (d. 1678).
      1 p., torn; 16 x 21 cm.
      "Mr Clayton I desire you will pay
      unto this bearer Mr Stayley the summ
      of three hundred pound."
  - ARUNDELL OF WARDOUR, THOMAS ARUNDELL, BARON, 1633-1712
    - ALS to Sir Robert Clayton (1628-1707), 1665 May 8 (Box 1)
      requesting payment to Sir Thomas
      Bond. Endorsed with receipt, signed
      and in the hand of Bond, 1665 May 9.
      1 p.; 21 x 15 cm.
  - ARUNDELL OF WARDOUR, THOMAS ARUNDELL, BARON, 1633-1712
    - ALS to Sir Robert Clayton (1628-1707), 1665 May 17 (Box 1)
      requesting payment. Endorsed with
      receipt, signed and in the hand of
      George Messenger, 1665 May 17.
      1 p.; 18 x 15 cm.
  - ARUNDELL OF TRERICE, RICHARD ARUNDELL, BARON, D. 1687
    - LS to Sir Robert Clayton (1628-1707), 1671 Oct 2 (Box 1)
      Trerice.
      Proposes to Clayton that his son
      marry "a young Lady, of a
      Considerable Fortune, in wch. you
      are Concern'd."
      1 p.; 26 x 18 cm.
  - ARUNDELL OF TRERICE, RICHARD ARUNDELL, BARON, D. 1687
    - LS to Sir Robert Clayton (1628-1707), 1671 Oct 26 (Box 1)
      Concerns the proposed marriage of
      his son, discussed in his letter to
      Clayton of 1671 Oct 2. "Sr. Your
      Civill, and friendly Letter, I have
      receiv'd."
      1 p.; 29 x 21 cm.
  - ARUNDELL OF WARDOUR, THOMAS ARUNDELL, BARON, 1633-1712
    - ALS to Humphry? Morice (Morrice) (1640?-96), 1672 Mar 28 (Box 1)
      Concerns the deed of a mortgage.
      Mentions a Mr. Bennet and Sir Walter
      Long.
  - NORFOLK, HENRY HOWARD, 7TH DUKE OF, 1655-1701.
    - Document, signed, 1678 Dec 18 (Box 1)
      Signed Arundell.
      Acknowledges receipt of £500 from
      Richard Franklyn and John Wyse.
      1 p.; 31 x 19 cm.
      Witnessed by Matthew Scott, Peter
      Clayton, and Sir Anthony Keck
      (1630-95), with their signatures.
      Henry Howard, son and heir apparent
      to the duke of Norfolk, was styled
      Earl of Arundel 1677-84, and Baron
      Mowbray, 1679.
  - NORFOLK, HENRY HOWARD, 7TH DUKE OF, 1655-1701
    - Document, signed, 1680 Nov 23 (Box 1)
      Promises to pay £10,600 to Richard
      Franklyn and John Wyse.
      1 p.; 36 x 23 cm.
      Witnessed by Francis Negus (d. 1732),
      Sir Anthony Keck (1630-95), and
      Friamor (?) Baldwin, with their